<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Insaaanimanav&#39;s blog </title>
    <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Insaaanimanav&#39;s blog </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://insaanimanav.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Next up Forever</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/next-up-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/next-up-forever/</guid>
      <description>So this is the first one in a series of blog posts I am going to write about songs that I like and which are very close to my heart. I frankly just wanted to pour out my thoughts about some things and I realized that since nobody visits this corner of the web so why not here.
The basic essence of this song this how anything seems better when it is about to come up and seems meh when you are finally experiencing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One year of engineering</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/one_year_of_engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/one_year_of_engineering/</guid>
      <description>Why Engineering  If I throw a stone from my house in any direction, I am sure to hit atleast 2 people who have an enginering degree
  A common saying in India  I was recently talking to an aquintance of mine helping him install Linux on his machine and in the middle of our conversation he said and I quote
Tu kya ye open-source karta rehta hai .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signing Git commits</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/signing_commits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/signing_commits/</guid>
      <description>But why do I need to sign my commits Git is cryptographically secure. But as with most things on the internet, you can&amp;rsquo;t trust what you see. But you don&amp;rsquo;t have to extremely skeptical either, the least you can do is ensure that whatever stuff you put on there is trusted and verified.
What exactly Is GPG? GPG stands for GnuPG which is a free implementation of the OpenPGP standard for encryption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Profile Level Readme</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/profile-readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/profile-readme/</guid>
      <description>Github Profile README GitHub recently released a feature that allows users to create a profile-level README to display on their GitHub profile. This article will help you to access this new feature.
I&amp;rsquo;ll also be sharing some fun GitHub profiles I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far. If you create yours don&amp;rsquo;t forget it to share it with me on twitter @insaanimanav .
Why README&amp;rsquo;s This feature allows much more than what you can currently do with your bio on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Open Source Note taking</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/joplin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/joplin/</guid>
      <description>Taking notes the open-source style Joplin is an open-source note-taking application that is also cross-platform so your notes and todos get synced whether you are on android or your desktop. So without any further ado, Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it
Install and Setup Joplin provides an amazing install script to get you up and running in no time in case of Linux
wget -O - https://raw.githubusercontent.com/laurent22/joplin/master/Joplin_install_and_update.sh | bash Just copy and paste this into your terminal and this will fetch the latest version of Joplin and install it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OS Wars part 2</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/os_wars_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/os_wars_2/</guid>
      <description>OS wars part 2 So It&amp;rsquo;s the year 1991, Microsoft and Apple have been trading blows for decades now and finally the war ground is about to settle, then comes along Linux and s, Microsoft reals and regroups. Now Imagine if you are Microsoft in 1991, With assured global dominance things are looking pretty good for you. But you are still cutting out the main heroes of the story ie the software developers, sysadmins, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDE connect-The companion app that we deserve</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/kde_connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/kde_connect/</guid>
      <description>KDE connect - &amp;ldquo;The companion app that we deserve&amp;rdquo; Linking my phone with my computer has always been of concern. I mean, If I want to send a file to my computer, How do I do it? Email it to me? Somehow send it to me on Telegram? All these are tedious ways and not very efficient in nature. One fix if you are a techie is to use maybe create a wrapper around SFTP(Simple File Transfer Protocol) and use it to send files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Linux command Line</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/command_line_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/command_line_intro/</guid>
      <description>cd command cd stands for change directory putting the directory name in front of the cd command lets you change to that directory A little caveat is that /home/username is your main home directory which is the default for all terminal editors and that is also aliased to ~ Basically both of these are the same
cd /home/insaanimanav/Videos cd ~/Videos This is probably the single most useful command that you will use while using the command line</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OS Wars Part 1</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/os_wars_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/os_wars_1/</guid>
      <description>Some stories are so epic , with such high stakes that it seems like their introduction is almost like the star wars rolling intro
It is a period of mounting tension in the world as two huge empires are fighting on getting a monopoly in the software market using their proprietary software, meanwhile in a distant land open source rebels have started to gather
Part 1 - Get out of this box It&amp;rsquo;s 1983 Ronald Regan is the president of the United States; I was around -18 years old and the US and Soviet Union is threatening the world with a nuclear war .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I am Manav Sethi an Undergrad student in my second year. I like to contribute to OSS software at KDEI go by the pseudonym @insaanimanav on the web, reach out to me on telegram or on matrix(insaanimanav:matrix.org)Reach out me on email at manav.sethi@outlook.inDisclaimer Here are some of my known biases :
 I only use , recommend and evaluate things that are truly Free I value the hacker ethic above everything I only talk about something I follow myself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>