<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Insaaanimanav&#39;s blog </title>
    <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Insaaanimanav&#39;s blog </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Signing Git commits</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/signing_commits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/signing_commits/</guid>
      <description>But why do I need to sign my commits Git is cryptographically secure. But as with most things on the internet, you can&amp;rsquo;t trust what you see. But you don&amp;rsquo;t have to extremely skeptical either, the least you can do is ensure that whatever stuff you put on there is trusted and verified.
What exactly Is GPG? GPG stands for GnuPG which is a free implementation of the OpenPGP standard for encryption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Profile Level Readme</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/profile-readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/profile-readme/</guid>
      <description>Github Profile README GitHub recently released a feature that allows users to create a profile-level README to display on their GitHub profile. This article will help you to access this new feature.
I&amp;rsquo;ll also be sharing some fun GitHub profiles I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far. If you create yours don&amp;rsquo;t forget it to share it with me on twitter @insaanimanav .
Why README&amp;rsquo;s This feature allows much more than what you can currently do with your bio on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Open Source Note taking</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/joplin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/joplin/</guid>
      <description>Taking notes the open-source style Joplin is an open-source note-taking application that is also cross-platform so your notes and todos get synced whether you are on android or your desktop. So without any further ado, Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it
Install and Setup Joplin provides an amazing install script to get you up and running in no time in case of Linux
wget -O - https://raw.githubusercontent.com/laurent22/joplin/master/Joplin_install_and_update.sh | bash Just copy and paste this into your terminal and this will fetch the latest version of Joplin and install it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OS Wars part 2</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/os_wars_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/os_wars_2/</guid>
      <description>OS wars part 2 So It&amp;rsquo;s the year 1991, Microsoft and Apple have been trading blows for decades now and finally the war ground is about to settle, then comes along Linux and s, Microsoft reals and regroups. Now Imagine if you are Microsoft in 1991, With assured global dominance things are looking pretty good for you. But you are still cutting out the main heroes of the story ie the software developers, sysadmins, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDE connect-The companion app that we deserve</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/kde_connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/kde_connect/</guid>
      <description>KDE connect - &amp;ldquo;The companion app that we deserve&amp;rdquo; Linking my phone with my computer has always been of concern. I mean, If I want to send a file to my computer, How do I do it? Email it to me? Somehow send it to me on Telegram? All these are tedious ways and not very efficient in nature. One fix if you are a techie is to use maybe create a wrapper around SFTP(Simple File Transfer Protocol) and use it to send files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Linux command Line</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/command_line_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/command_line_intro/</guid>
      <description>Intro to the command line One of the most powerful tools while using Linux is the Linux command line . Because you see Linux was never meant to be used as a desktop . In the Initial days of Linux it was completely used without a graphical interface right in the server room . Thats why the linux command line is so powerful.
Before talking about anything we need to get some basics in place</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OS Wars Part 1</title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/os_wars_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/os_wars_1/</guid>
      <description>Some stories are so epic , with such high stakes that it seems like their introduction is almost like the star wars rolling intro
It is a period of mounting tension in the world as two huge empires are fighting on getting a monopoly in the software market using their proprietary software, meanwhile in a distant land open source rebels have started to gather
Part 1 - Get out of this box It&amp;rsquo;s 1983 Ronald Regan is the president of the United States; I was around -18 years old and the US and Soviet Union is threatening the world with a nuclear war .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/one_year_of_engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insaanimanav.github.io/post/one_year_of_engineering/</guid>
      <description>Why Engineering  If I throw a stone from my house in any direction, I am sure to hit atleast 2 people who have an enginering degree
  A common saying in India  I was recently talking to an aquintance of mine helping him install Linux on his machine and in the middle of our conversation he said and I quote
Tu kya ye open-source karta rehta hai .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>